Hello English learners,
welcome back to another
advanced lesson with
us here at English pod.
My name is Marco.
And my name's Erica.
So today we're bringing
you another advanced
lesson and this time
it's kind of historical.
Like the name suggests,
we are listening in as
a president says goodbye
to the nation before
he steps down from
his role as president.
Now actually this
dialogue is very much based
on President Eisenhower's
fellow well speech.
Okay, so a pretty famous,
now we have to tell
you that we did change
the speech a little bit, right?
Just a little bit to
make it a little bit
more understandable, but it's basically
what he said to the nation back in 1969.
All right, now I will as well tell you
that this is a pretty hard dialogue.
It is very hard because
the structures are a
little bit complicated and even to a
certain point, a little bit poetic, right?
So why are we taking
this speech as our
dialogue, what are we
going to learn from this?
Well we're going to
learn some structures and
some words that you can
use maybe on a resignation
letter or maybe in a celebration
you want to thank Pete for coming.
Okay, so we're going
to learn some pretty
difficult vocabulary but
also learn some really
useful structures like
you said you could use
in a resignation letter
or even in a formal
speech of your own.
Exactly, now this
presidential farewell speech
is divided into two
parts, so today we're
going to do part one and then next
time we'll finish the speech with part two.
So let's listen to
President Eisenhower as
he says goodbye to the nation
and we'll come back just in a little bit.
Good evening, by fellow Americans.
Three days from now,
after a century of service to
our country, I shall lay
down the responsibilities
of office as in a traditional
and solemn ceremony,
the authority of the presidency
is vested in my successor.
This evening I come to
you with a message of
leave taking and farewell and to share a
few final thoughts with you, my countrymen.
Like every other citizen,
I wish the new president
and all who will leave
her with him, God's bead.
I pray that the coming years will be
blessed with peace and prosperity for all.
Our people expect
their president and the
Congress to find essential
agreement on questions
of great importance, the
wise resolution of which
will better shape the
future of our great nation.
My own relations with
Congress began on a
remote, an continuous
basis when, long ago, a
member of the Senate
appointed me to West Point.
I then had the pleasure
of building more
intimate relationships with Congress during
the war and the immediate postwar period.
Finally, we have
progressed to the mutually
interdependent relationship we've
had during these past eight years.
Wow, so Eisenhower is a
pretty good speaker, isn't he?
A good speaker and
well, he said a lot of
really nice things when
he was saying goodbye.
Yeah, pretty inspiring, I thought.
Really inspiring.
And as we said, there were a couple of
different and difficult words and phrases.
So why don't we start right
now with language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Well, Eisenhower said that in three days,
he shall lay down the responsibilities.
To lay down the responsibilities.
All right, lay down something.
Basically we understand
the verb to lay
down, right, to put it down,
to put it on the ground.
Right.
Now, he's using it
with responsibilities,
which is a little bit
strange, but it's kind
of like a metaphor by saying lay
down arms to lay down your weapons.
Right, and you know
what, this is a really
common phrase that
we would hear, especially
when we're talking
about the end of a war or
something like that, to lay down your
arms with your down your weapons.
So here I think
Eisenhower is kind of
referencing this and giving us a little
bit of a bit of poetry in his speech.
Right.
So it's not that he's
quitting, it's not that
he's being fired, he's just
like finishing what he started.
Yes, so he's laying
down his responsibilities.
Now, I think this would
be quite an interesting
phrase to use, for example,
in a resignation letter.
Right, so I would say
a month from now, I
will lay down my
responsibilities as manager.
Yep.
All right, so that sounds pretty good.
Now, he said he's going
to be laying down the
responsibilities in a traditional
and solemn ceremony.
All right, solemn.
solemn.
Now, solemn, what does that mean?
What is a solemn ceremony?
Well, a solemn ceremony would be a serious,
respectful, and a little bit sad ceremony.
Okay, so it's a serious
matter, and it's very respectful.
Yeah, so you might say, for example, on the
11th of November, when you're remembering
the war, you might say something
like, this is a very solemn day.
Very good.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, and the authority of the
presidency is vested in my successor.
Okay, so interesting verb, uh, no,
so interesting word, vested, vested.
The authority vested in my successor.
Very good.
This word basically means
power that I have by law.
Right.
So this power, this
important power you have
is given to you by the law, by
the president, by the country.
This is a very common word
you will hear in a wedding.
Mm-hmm.
When the priest or the
person that's leading
the wedding will say, by the power
vested in me, by the state of California.
Yep.
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
So you're saying the power
that I have given to me by
the state of California, I can
now make you be married.
So here, Eisenhower
is saying, the authority
of the presidency is
vested in my successor.
So the power of the
presidency will be given
to his, um, given to the
next, next president by law.
Hey, exactly.
And he also wished the new president
and everyone with him, he said, Godspeed.
All right, Godspeed.
Godspeed.
I wish you Godspeed.
Now, Godspeed, what does that mean?
Well, it's kind of a
blessing, you know, um,
it basically means good
luck and good fortune.
All right.
And especially in a journey.
Yeah, I think you'd
almost only use this
when someone's going off
on a, on a big trip or a journey.
So, um, here, they're going on
the journey of the presidency.
Right.
Very good.
So I wish you Godspeed.
Godspeed.
Very good.
And now let's take a
look at our last set of
words, uh, when he was
talking about Congress
he said that his relation with Congress
began on a remote and tenuous basis.
All right.
So two interesting words
here, remote and tenuous.
Now remote, we understand
as being far away or distant.
Yeah.
What about tenuous, though?
But tenuous is kind of
unimportant or not really relevant.
All right.
So actually, this is a pretty high quality,
um, useful and smart sounding word.
So I think we should hear a few
more examples of how it's used.
Example one.
How can you say the earth
is actually getting cooler?
That is a pretty tenuous argument.
Example two.
John believes that
Elvis Presley is still alive.
He's got a tenuous hold on reality.
Example three.
We're making yourself seem
more important than you are.
Connections between our community success
and your performance is tenuous at best.
All right.
So as we said, these are
some pretty, um, pretty
difficult words that we
found in the dialogue.
But now I want to go
and look at some really
interesting, um, formal structures
that Eisenhower used here.
So let's look at those
now and fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right.
I'm fluency builder today.
We have three phrases
and while starting with
the first one, I think it's one
of the most interesting ones.
He said three days
from now after a half a
century of service of our country, I shall
lay down the responsibilities of office.
All right.
So what's interesting about this?
If you take a look
at the structure, he's
saying three days from
now, which is future, future.
And then he makes a reference to
the past after a half century of service.
Okay, so we got future
past and then again,
future I shall lay down
the responsibilities.
All right.
So this actually is quite a good structure.
If you're giving a
farewell speech or even,
even I could imagine
using this at a wedding.
Right.
How would you use it in a wedding?
Well, I might say,
um, 12 hours for now
after a long and beautiful
relationship, this couple shall marry.
Very good.
And then the future
and then a past event or
something that's been
going on for a while.
And then future again.
Why don't we do one more example?
So for example, in a
resignation letter, I can
say, uh, I can say one
month from now after
30 years of hard work
and dedication to this
company, I shall lay down my
responsibilities as product manager.
All right.
Interesting.
So we can use it and it sounds good.
It sounds very
professional and very poetic.
Very poetic.
Nice.
Yeah.
All right.
So that's one interesting structure.
Now why don't we go
on to this next kind of
very formal and helpful
in a, in a very formal
speech?
Well, uh, President
Eisenhower said, this
evening I come to you with a
message of leave taking and farewell.
So this evening I come to you with a
So it's a very nice way
of saying, I'm talking
to you today because
I am saying goodbye.
Yes.
What I really like about this
phrase is the beginning part.
This evening I come to
you with a message of,
so again, let's suppose
we're at a wedding.
Uh huh.
I'm offering a toast or I'm
the best man I could say.
This evening I come to you with a
message of love and trust and respect.
All right.
Or maybe if you're the
leader of a company,
you might say something
like this afternoon,
I come to you with a
message of hope for the future.
Very good.
Now the part when
he says leave taking and
farewell, it's basically saying taking
leave or taking like a vacation, right?
Yeah.
Farewell.
Goodbye.
And what about our last phrase?
Uh, this is actually a bit of a long one.
So I'm going to read it now.
Are people expect
their president and the
Congress to find essential
agreement on questions
of great importance, the
wise resolution of which
will better shape the
future of our great nation?
Okay.
Great.
Now let's take a look at the first part.
Basically he's saying,
uh, the people expect
the president and the Congress
to give them answers, right?
Or yeah, to agree on,
on important issues, but
in the part when he
says the wise resolution
of which will better shape
the future of our great nation.
Yeah.
And this is the part I want to focus
on, the wise resolution of which.
Now this is a really wonderful
sort of a formal structure.
So we can see what he's doing here.
He's talking about the first idea, right?
So the president and the Congress need to
find agreement on important issues, right?
Now the wise resolution of which,
so he's referring back to that idea.
Uh huh.
So the wise resolution of what?
Of the essential agreement on
questions of great importance.
Right.
So really useful structure.
Why don't we hear a few
more examples of this?
The whole one.
We now face a great challenge.
The overcoming of which lead
us all to untold riches and success.
Example two.
We as a company now face
our most difficult months
to date, the outcome of which
will determine our company's future.
Example three.
The ambitious plan to reduce poverty, the
start of which was launched last Tuesday in
New York will require a huge
investment of tax payers dollars.
All right.
So as you can hear
from the examples, we
have the main idea and then he passes on,
but then kind of refers back to it again.
Yeah.
And this sounds quite formal, but
also quite literary and intelligent.
That's it.
It makes, it makes you
sound well spoken, very good.
This was quite a
difficult dialogue with
some really interesting and
tricky structures and words.
Why don't we hear one
more time all together?
Good evening.
My fellow Americans.
Three days from now,
after a century of service to
our country, I shall lay
down the responsibilities
of office as in a traditional
and solemn ceremony,
the authority of the presidency
is vested in my successor.
This evening I come to
you with a message of
leave taking and farewell and to share a
few final thoughts with you, my countrymen.
Like every other
citizen, I wish the new
president and all who will
leave her with him, Godspeed.
I pray that the coming years will be
blessed with peace and prosperity for all.
Our people expect
their president and the
Congress to find essential
agreement on questions
of great importance, the
wise resolution of which
will better shape the
future of our great nation.
My own relations with
Congress began on a remote
and tenuous basis when, long ago, a member
of the Senate appointed me to West Point.
I then had the pleasure
of building more
intimate relationships with Congress during
the war and the immediate postwar period.
Finally, we have
progressed to the mutually
interdependent relationship we've
had during these past eight years.
All right, we're back
and here with us in
the studio, we have
Pete of the actor in the
dialogue of President Eisenhower's
presidential farewell speech.
She's a pretty convincing actor at that.
Not quite.
So Pete is going to give us a little bit of
insight about President Eisenhower will.
All right, so what can you tell
us about President Eisenhower?
Well, he started off as a general he was an
accomplished officer all through the early
20th century and then he
was the supreme commander
of the Allied Expeditionary
Force in World War II.
And so now he's most famous for D-Day.
He was leading it or
he was on the battlefield
or he was he was
he was the organizer.
He was he was the kind of like
the the brains behind the operation.
Yeah, I don't know if
you want to leave this
in, but there's a there's
a really cool document
that he wrote right
before the invasion and
it said he basically
knew that this was going
to go one of two ways
and he wrote down a script
to read in case it
failed and he basically
said, you know, I'm
sorry to inform you that
the invasion did not
go as planned and this
is setback our war effort
and when the invasion
went well he threw that in the trash and
then one of his aides found out and was
like, wow, this is a historical
document and they kept the.
Oh, really?
So they had the they have
the copy alternate history.
All right, so he was an
accomplished general and
amazing warrior, but
what about his presidency?
Well, at the beginning,
probably the biggest
thing he did was to
wrap up the Korean war,
which was a vow he made during his
campaign and then he visited Korea.
Obviously the war is still technically
on, but they did arrange a cease fire.
Eisenhower built up the
interstate highway system,
which is one of the
big reasons that America
was able to become economically
successful in the 20th century.
He did it basically so
that in case of a war,
we have an easy way
of shipping our soldiers
and nukes across the country,
but it worked well anyway.
It's one of these things
that pays aside benefit,
at least he had to sell it
to the country that way.
It's very likely that
he didn't intend ever
to use it that way, but you know, you have
to have like, it's like the war on terror.
You got to sell these things.
Well, and I guess it's
had a huge impact not
only on the economy
of the states, but also
like the culture and the way that people
view the car and it's a fact on society.
Definitely.
So a pretty influential
guy, this Eisenhower.
Yeah, and a very
historical lesson is just a
little bit of a culture and maybe
some insight on American history.
It's not like we're politically active or
anything, but yeah, it was some interesting
information there and also, well, he was
considered to be a pretty good president.
Yeah, he's really, I wouldn't say among
the top five or so, but quite accomplished.
Well, maybe not the
greatest president we've
ever seen, but he wrote
a pretty good farewell
speech, so I think we
have that to thank him for.
All right, guys, so if
you have any other
questions or comments, you
can come to the website at www.
EnglishPod.com, and you can
leave them there for Erica or I.
Okay, so thanks for downloading
you guys, and until next time, goodbye.
Bye.